## Lilliana Ramos

Email: lilliana.cramos@gmail.com | Phone: 787-219-7682 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/lillianaramos/ Github: github.com/lilliana1 Portfolio: lilliana-ramos-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer who holds a Bachelors in Information Technology from UPR-RP. Experienced in data entry and technical support. Team player with an eye for detail and capacity to adapt, learn fast and handle sensitive information. Equipped to execute multiple tasks to create products for customer satisfaction.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Front End:** HTML5,CSS,Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, Foundation **API Interaction:** APIs, JSON, AJAX, Real Time Cloud Database via Firebase

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Server-Side: Node.js, Express.js, ORM (Sequelize), MVC

Other: React.js

Dev Tools: Heroku, Git, Github

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Appetite | Appetite Github | Appetite Website**

- Appetite is a real-time restaurant finder app using Yelp's API. Able to explore and review restaurants.
- Personal project. Responsible for all front and back end.
- MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, Bootstrap, Axios, bcrypt-JS, Passport.

## **Corner Market | Corner Market Github | Corner Market Website**

- Corner Market is an app built for easy viewing large amounts of products in a user friendly way. This is a complete CRUD app.
- Group project. Responsible for all front-end work from UI to making data appear on page. Worked with Foundation and Handlebars.
- HTML,CSS, Foundation, Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MYSQL, Sequelize,bcrypt-JS, Passport.

## Make Me Laugh | Make Me Laugh Github | Make Me Laugh Website

- Make Me Laugh is a "time-waster" website, designed purely for fun. You will find jokes, funny sounds, gifs, and random events will occur during the experience.
- Group project. Responsible of all HTML, CSS and animation on the webpage using animate.css
- HTML, CSS, Materialize, JS, jQuery

#### EXPERIENCE

## Technical Assistant | Office Clerk Dr. Eric Ramos Medical Office

2013 – 2019 San Lorenzo, PR

- Increased the efficiency of performance by digitizing documents to facilitate the process of inputs.
- Provided technical support to office devices such as printer, fax, scanner, copy and any computer, internet or network connectivity issues when called.
- Created documents, scanned hard copy files to electronic images and handled correspondence which contained delicate information about a patient's health.
- Assisted the Doctor with importing information of patients into EHR.

# Data Entry Specialist J. Maris Financial Services, INC

2018 – 2018 West Palm Beach, FL

• Inputted and verified large volumes of data from various sources and entered it to Microsoft Excel Application for import purposes within a quick turnaround time.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bootcamp Certificate:**

2019-2020

University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

## **Bootcamp Certificate:**

2019-2019

Code Trotters, San Juan, PR

A 10-week entry level course that dives deep into the fundamentals of Javascript, OOP and Node.js

## **Computer Information Systems Degree:**

2013-2018

University of Puerto Rico, Rio Piedras, PR

Emphasizes the implementation and use of technology and information systems in the environment of business enterprises and government organizations. Also highlights the technical, functional and administrative aspects of the information systems components, as well as how these components are integrated into solutions to solve problems in these organizations.